<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prashant&#39;s Nook</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Prashant&#39;s Nook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 12:58:29 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>E Paper Kiosk</title>
      <link>/post/e-paper-kiosk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 12:58:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/e-paper-kiosk/</guid>
      <description>Greetings everyone,
Recently I have been interning as a Research Intern at IIIT Hyderabad in Smart City Research Center.
this is the very first photo I took inside.. and yea I know my camera glitched up*
It&amp;rsquo;s been really fun working with cool stuff and having access to makers lab, which is an absolute Hardware haven. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on some basic projects with neopixels and stuff which I&amp;rsquo;ve already worked with at my home with the TV ambilight setup with prismatik and Adalight FastLED.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rocket PID Stability</title>
      <link>/post/pid-rocket-stability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 01:38:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/pid-rocket-stability/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone!
Last semester we had a course on Control Systems, where we learned about controlling systems and how to design their controllers. As a huge fan of Boston dynamics Spot and their various robots, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been curious about how they work.
The very first time I was introduced to robotics was back in 5th grade&amp;rsquo;s Summer Camp, where we had to build robots like Line following and Path navigating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 08:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Simulation Rocket Stablity Controller Using PID Controller for rocket stability. --- Linear Antenna Phase Shader Phased Antenna Direction modelling in a linear antenna array.
--- Newton Fractal Shader Solving complex cubic polynomial using newton raphson method
--- Lorenz attractor --- Blender Vector Fields --- Games Worst Tank This is a collaborative entry to itch.io&amp;rsquo;s weekly gamejam.
WorstTank {Beta} by Pacchu, brrrr --- Torch Runner This is an entry to ludam-dare gamejam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Contact</title>
      <link>/post/first-contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 03:12:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-contact/</guid>
      <description>First-ish contact First contact is essential for peace keeping between races so here&amp;rsquo;s my first contact. Hello I am Prashant and this is a blog which I&amp;rsquo;m hopefully gonna update. Cheers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Double_pendulum</title>
      <link>/post/double_pendulum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 22:12:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/double_pendulum/</guid>
      <description>Lately Youtube has been recommending me random Chaos theory videos and how small changes to input of a system can lead to huge changes in the Output.
The Output of system diverges vastly from the input even for very small difference in initial input conditions. Me being the type of person I am, decided to make a double pendulum system, cause processing is a really fun library to play around with and I wanted to try it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inverse Kinematics</title>
      <link>/post/inverse_kinematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 19:39:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/inverse_kinematics/</guid>
      <description>++++ This post is mirrored from here
This project started off in exploring the Inverse Kinematics. Inverse kinematics piqued my interest when I started watching MIT maker portfolio videos and stumbled on a 5 arm chain Robot arm. I&amp;rsquo;ve always wondered how IK systems work in blender or cinema4D and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d explore.
The first method I stumbled on was Isoceles triangle approach where you compute angles assuming symmetricity of Isoceles triangle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fourier Series Epicycloid</title>
      <link>/post/fourier_series_epicycloid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 15:18:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fourier_series_epicycloid/</guid>
      <description>++++ This post is mirrored from here
Fourier Series is a mathematical technique that is used to approximate the shape of a curve by decomposing signal into frequency components.
Complex Fourier Series Attempt #1 : Havent done much except trying to pick out a backend to work this thing on &amp;hellip; thought of using Cinema4D but due to lack of its precision on floating point integers coudn&amp;rsquo;t get it to work with my initial values And here&#39;s me messing with Cinema4D with rotating circles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worst Tank Project</title>
      <link>/post/worst-tank-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 16:41:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/worst-tank-project/</guid>
      <description>++++ This post is mirrored from here
This is an entry to Itch.io&amp;rsquo;s Weekly Game Jam #150. Play on Github pages This is the first gamejam I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to team up with someone random from the internet. Which was really cool for working in a team under a time crunch.
This fella is my teammate
The main theme of this gamejam was **You are the enemy** which was first very confusing and we had literally no idea what to even do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Modulation Techniques</title>
      <link>/post/digital_modulation_techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 15:04:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/digital_modulation_techniques/</guid>
      <description>++++ This post is mirrored from here
visualizations Amplitude Shift keying Frequency Shift keying Quantization principle Delta Modulation Amplitude modulation This is completly made using Cinema4D and python-c4d Source Rest all the modulations are generated by simply switching input signal to various parameters of the signal. Delta Modulation Since Delta modulation is a bit different , the setup arrange is checking for the difference (0,1). </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lorentz Attractor</title>
      <link>/post/lorentz-attractor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:22:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lorentz-attractor/</guid>
      <description>++++ This post is mirrored from here
So this is Lorentz attractor written in blender-python and grease pencil, Lorentz attractor is a differential equation used to simulate 2D fluid flow mainly Atmospheric convection. This is a preview of what i made So how did i approach making this trippy beautiful simulation , Basically differential equations Lorentz attractor is governed by 3 differential equation on each of its axis Governed by 3 differential equations These equations induvially control the way the fluid flows in a corresponding domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the person</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2001 02:49:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>
Greeting humans!
I am Prashant, an undergraduate Electronics and Communication Student.
I have a keen interest in Mathematical modelling, Robotics and building Electronic contraptions. Building visualisations and interactive systems for the concepts been taught and watching them in action is the most fun part of building things.
Interests Programatical Mathematics. Electronics and Robotics. GameJams. Cycling. Badminton. Interesting Stuff I like Essense of Algebra
Book of shaders
Sebastian Lague
Music </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title># Other Links</title>
      <link>/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/links/</guid>
      <description> LinkedIn Github Reddit Discord (pacchu#4112) Spotify Lastfm Instagram Twitter </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cinema4d Grapher</title>
      <link>/post/cinema4d_grapher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cinema4d_grapher/</guid>
      <description>++++ This post is mirrored from here
Cinema4D Math Graphing using Matrix plane building a This is a simple test project i wanted to build ... to generate 3D XY plots in Cinema4D. How does it work? A plane is generated with z = 0 if we iterate through the x and y axes &amp;hellip; by injecting a function and taking the corresponding Z value we can basically plot stuff in cinema4D (I know thats how basically every graphing thing works)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid SRI Model</title>
      <link>/post/covid_sri_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/covid_sri_model/</guid>
      <description>++++ This post is mirrored from here
Standard SRI model refers to Suseceptance population ( those who can be infected from the virus ) , Infected (duh) , Recovered/Dead .. by solving differential equations
S = Susceptance population R = Recovered/Dead I = Infected
where α is the r_o value of Covid19 its negative as people get infected the total susecptance population drops (ie people get sick) here β is the recovery coefficient of Covid19 its negative as infected people either gain immunity or die due to virus .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
